我们在天上的父,
Our Father who art in Heaven,
愿人都尊你的名为圣,
hallowed be thy Name,
愿你的国降临,
thy kingdom come,
愿你的旨意...
thy will be done...
别在赛道上停下来
Don't stop on the track.
现在还不能习惯
It's too early for you to get used to it.
爱，不要放弃
Love, don't give up
别在赛道上停下来
Don't stop on the track
朝圣之旅保罗·柯艾略的精彩故事
现在还不能习惯
It's too early for you to get used to it
爱，不要放弃
Love, don't give up
如果你停下来，车可能会撞到你
If you stop, the car might get you
嘟嘟，嘟嘟，拨浪鼓
Beep-beep, honk-honk, rattle-rattle
如果你停下来，车可能会撞到你
If you stop, the car might get you
你一直说我是个疯子
You keep calling me a crazy maniac
世界在转动，而我们却静止不动
The world is turning and we're standing still
亲爱的，把手给我，我来扶你
Honey, give me your hand, I'm going to take you
没有车，也不怕被警察开罚单
With no car and no fear to get a ticket from the cop
亲爱的，把手给我，我来扶你
Honey, give me your hand, I'm going to take you
没有车，没有恐惧
With no car and no fear somewhere else
别在赛道上停下来
Don't stop on the track
现在还不能习惯
It's too early for you to get used to it
爱，不要放弃
Love, don't give up
如果你停下来，车可能会撞到你
If you stop, the car might get you
嘟嘟，嘟嘟，拨浪鼓
Beep-beep, honk-honk, rattle-rattle
如果你停下来，车可能会撞到你
If you stop, the car might get you
妈妈，爸爸，哥哥！
Mom, dad, brother!
如果你停下来，车可能会撞到你
If you stop, the car might get you
奶奶，宝贝，莉莉
Grandma, baby, Lili
如果你停下来，车可能会撞到你
If you stop, the car might get you
里约热内卢，20世纪60 年代
RIO DE JANEIRO, 1960s
保罗·柯艾略·德·索萨。
Paulo Coelho de Souza.
来吧，孩子。
Come, son.
别管他。
Leave him.
让他自己去吧。
He'll go by himself.
“我想死，因为一切都是错的。
‟I want to die because everything's wrong.
活着没有意义。
There is no point in keeping on living.
上帝应该为 让我经历这些 而道歉”
God should apologize for making me go through this.”
保罗,
Paulo,
我问你点事。
let me ask you something.
你真的没交过女朋友吗？
Is it true you've never had a girlfriend?
为什么不交呢？
Why not?
因为我很丑。
Because I'm ugly.
这就是你要自杀的原因吗？
Is that why you tried to kill yourself?
保罗,
Paulo,
你有没有想过去亲一个男人？
have you ever felt like kissing a man?
这个人也许是你朋友或熟人？
Maybe a friend or an acquaintance?
别担心。
Don't worry.
你父母很担心，但一切都会好起来的。
Your parents are worried, but everything will be all right.
- 同性恋?	                - 说完了吗？
- Homosexuality.	- Are we done?
等等，坐下。
Wait, sit down.
我们再谈谈。
Let's talk a little bit more.
我想成为一名作家。
I want to be a writer.
我从没想过做别的事。
I've never wanted to be something else.
但这是好事。
But that's a good thing.
写作是件好事。
Writing is a good thing.
这是一种组织我们的感觉和想法的方式。
It's a way of organizing how we feel, what we think.
- 不是吗?		-是真的。
- Isn't it?		- It's true.
职业呢? 你选择职业了吗？
What about a profession? Have you chosen a profession?
我想成为一名作家。
I want to be a writer.
你觉得会有人想读
Do you think anyone will want to read
你写的关于你自己的东西吗？
the things you write about yourself?
结束了吗？
Is it over now?
我想我父母在等我。
I think my parents are waiting for me.
我不确定我们做对了。
I'm not sure we did the right thing.
事情已经发生了，我们必须面对。
It's already done. We have to face it.
没人告诉我什么时候可以来看你。
No one told me when I can come visit.
- 我们会查出来的     - 他连衣服都没带
- We will find out. 	   - He didn't even bring clothes.
我们应该先问问的。
We should've asked.
我们走吧，克里斯。
Let's get out of here, Chris.
- 保罗		   -  我得马上离开这里。
- Paulo. 	   -  I need to get out of here now.
回去睡觉吧，你很虚弱。
Go back to bed. You're weak.
不，我感觉很好！
No, I'm feeling great!
你看到外面那些人了吗？
Do you see those people out there?
他们大多数人只是行尸走肉。
Most of them are only breathing.
我想活着死去。
I want to die living.
告诉莫妮卡我们要去派对。
Tell Monica we're going to the party.
不可能，你刚做完心脏手术。
No way. You've just had heart surgery.
不，只是个手术而已。
No, it was just a procedure.
你还没准备好参加派对。
You're not ready for a party.
这是我的派对，你想来吗？
It's my party. Do you want to come?
如果医生说你可以去，我们就去。
If the doctor says you can, we'll go.
不，我没时间浪费。
No, I don't have time to waste.
今天星期几? 他们今天来吗？
What day is today? Are they coming today?
第三周前不准探视。
No visitors before the third week.
- 还要多久?                       - 吃药吧。
- But how much longer?	   - Take your medication.
是弟子选择了他的师父。
It's the disciple who chooses his master.
西班牙，2013年
SPAIN, 2013
我们下车吧。
Let's get off.
我们不应该在这里下车。
We're not supposed to get off here.
现在到了。
Now we are.
莫妮卡都搞定了，有辆车在等我们。
Monica worked it all out, there's a car waiting for us.
我想抽根烟。
I want to smoke a cigarette.
保罗，我要去洗手间。
Paulo, I'm going to the bathroom.
《牧羊少年奇幻之旅（又名炼金术士）》，25年版
25 YEARS, THE ALCHEMIST
当你真心渴望某样东西时，
When you want something,
整个宇宙都会联合起来帮助你实现。
all the universe conspires in helping you achieve it.
你来参加我的派对吗？
Are you coming to my party?
你去吗？
Are you going?
我没想到你还在这种事上浪费时间。
I didn't think you still wasted your time with such things.
任何成就的秘诀...
The secret of any achievement...
就是知道该怎么做。
is knowing what to do with it.
我知道。
I know.
用派对来庆祝这个古老的成就
And is celebrating such an old achievement with a party
你能做到的最好？
the best you can do?
如果上帝...
If God...
上帝有比担心我更重要的事要做。
God has better things to do than worrying about me.
你也是。
And so do you.
帮我个忙。
Do me a favor.
把这个给克里斯。
Give this to Chris.
皮夹克... 你看起来很滑稽。
Leather jacket... You look funny.
- 离这里远吗?	              - 若不堵车，大约两小时车程。
- Is it far from here?     - About two hours without traffic.
我叫胡安, 很高兴认识你。
My name is Juan. It's a pleasure.
我喜欢为名人开车。
I love driving celebrities.
- 你是个作家，对吧?         - 是的。
- You're a writer, right?      - Yes, I am.
我想成为一名作家，靠讲故事为生。
I'd love to be a writer and live off telling stories.
这就是生活！
That's a life!
你写了《宇宙的正义》？
You wrote Justice of the Universe?
不，我知道了，你写了《炼金术士》。
No. I know, The Alchemist,  that one is yours.
我甚至用葡萄牙语读过。
I even read it in Portuguese.
我是加利西亚人，书与葡萄牙书基本一样。
I'm Galician, it's practically the same.
我太喜欢这本书！
I just loved it!
我不太记得了，因为我当时才15岁。
I don't remember it very well because I was 15.
当时读此书是学校布置的作业，但我很喜欢。
It was a school assignment, but I loved it.
我父母也读过，那是一本很棒的书！
My parents read it too. It's a great book!
谢谢。
Thanks.
我父亲也是个作家。
My father is a writer too.
不过也不是，他是殡仪馆的司机。
Well, not really. He's a driver at a funeral home.
但他也写作，是个诗人。
But he also writes, he's a poet.
他写得很好，很有才华。
He writes beautifully. He's really talented.
我是个演员，我想成为职业演员。
I'm an actor. I'd like to be a pro.
但我的时代还没到来。
But my time hasn't come yet.
不过我已是个演员。
But I'm an actor.
我希望能有所突破，这才是最重要的，要有运气。
I hope to get my break. That's what matters: luck.
请在这里停车。
Stop here, please.
上车。
Get in.
里约热内卢, 20世纪60年代
RIO DE JANEIRO, 1960s
跟我说说，保利尼奥。
Talk to me, Paulinho.
告诉我一些情况。
Tell me something.
我觉得你有点胖了。
I think you even gained some weight.
那里怎么样？
How was it there?
太棒了。
It was great.
我有个秘密要告诉你,
I have a secret to tell you,
但是答应我不要告诉你爸爸。
but promise me you won't tell your dad.
我买了比基尼,
I bought a bikini,
已经穿过两次了。
and I've worn it twice.
两次？
Twice?
佩德罗，求你了，让他休息吧。
Pedro, please. Let him rest.
明天等他醒了，你就可以和他说话了。
Tomorrow, when he wakes up, you can talk.
慢点，慢点。
Slowly, slowly.
来，慢慢来。
Come, slowly.
就是这样，继续。
That's it. Keep coming.
再来，再来。
More, more.
你更喜欢哪个？
Which do you prefer?
你想建的房子永远不会存在。
The house you want to build will never exist.
已经是了。
It already does.
你看不出来吗？
Can't you see?
坐一会儿。
Sit down for a moment.
保罗,
Paulo,
我做了我想做的一切。
everything I wanted in life, I did.
我想要在加维亚有个房子，我正在建,
I want the house in Gávea, and I'm building it,
尽我所能，一点一点地建，但我已在建造它。
as best as I can, little by little, but I'm building it.
不能看电影了，不能去旅行了,
No more movies, no more trips,
甚至连我求了你那么多次的打字机都没有！
not even the typewriter I've asked you for so many times!
一切都是为了你。
It's all about you.
- 都是为了你            - 我尽我所能，做了能做的事。
- It's all about you.    - I do what I can, what's possible.
我的梦想是有代价的。
There's a price for my dream.
你呢，你知道你想要什么吗？
What about you? Do you know what you want?
你知道我想要什么，你知道的。
You know what I want. You do.
我是认真的。
I mean it.
我很担心你。
I worry about you.
我说的是具体的事情,
I'm talking about concrete things,
做一个有目标的人。
about being someone, having a goal in life.
我想成为一个作家！
I want to be a writer!
没有人靠写作谋生！
No one makes a living by writing!
若昂· 卡布拉尔是个外交官，你知道吗？
João Cabral is a diplomat. Did you know that?
德拉蒙德是个公务员。
Drummond is a civil servant.
豪尔赫 · 阿马多是个记者。
Jorge Amado is a journalist.
你呢? 你想做什么，孩子？
What about you? What are you going to be, son?
佩德罗，你经常说...
Pedro, you often talk about...
里约热内卢，二十世纪八十年代
RIO DE JANEIRO, 1980s
关掉它，克里斯。
Turn this off, Chris.
这是什么鬼东西？
What the heck is this?
- 这首歌叫什么来着?	                    - 你知道的。
- What's this song called again?	    - You know.
应该是“我的丈夫保罗”
It should be ‟My Husband Paulo.”
饶了我吧！
Give me a break!
你饶了我吧！
You give me a break!
听着，我爱上了写这些歌的人,
Listen, I fell in love with the man who wrote those songs,
他梦想成为一名作家。
and dreamed about being a writer.
六年来我一直听到同样的故事。
I've been hearing the same story for six years.
可你一行字都没写。
You haven't written a single line.
你没看到我在努力吗？
Can't you see I'm trying?
努力? 怎么努力? 喝威士忌吗？
Trying? How? Drinking whiskey?
- 抱怨生活?	                          - 对我温柔点。
- Complaining about life?    - Go easy on me.
你想讲什么故事? 有一份你不喜欢的工作吗？
What story do you want to tell? Having a job you don't like?
赚你不需要的钱吗？
Earning money you don't need?
- 够了!	               - 这就是你的故事吗？
- Enough!           - Is that your story?
够了！
Enough!
怎么了，你不爱我了吗？
What's going on? Don't you love me anymore?
前嬉皮士,
An ex-hippie,
他现在穿的皮带和他的鞋子很配。
who now wears a belt that matches his shoes.
一个出色的作曲家
A brilliant songwriter
现在却成了一个愚蠢的音乐总监。
who's become a stupid music executive!
对不起，保罗，作家应该写作。
I'm sorry, Paulo, but a writer is supposed to write.
- 如果你放弃了,那么...			- 我永远不会放弃。
- If you've given up then... 	    -  I'll never give up.
那就写吧。
Then write.
做点有意义的事。
Do something with your life.
只有一次机会。
It's just one chance.
他只需要一次机会。
He just needs one chance.
这个男孩已准备好成为大热门了。
The boy is ready to become a hit.
这是他的人生轨迹，注定的。
It's his path. It's written.
从他小时候开始，他就一直在说这个。
Since he was little, that's all he talks about.
后来，我问他，“你知道成功是什么吗?”
Then I ask him, ‟Do you know what it is to be successful?”
他没有回答。
He doesn't.
我告诉他成功就是，“每个人都会为你鼓掌，都会爱你”。
‟Everyone will applaud you, will love you.”
但我也告诉他，“你也会挣扎。”。
But I also tell him, ‟You will also struggle.
所以你必须谦逊。
That's why you must be humble.
你必须努力工作。”
You have to work hard.”
当你注定要做某事时,
When you're destined to do something,
只有上帝能阻止你这么做。
only God can keep you from doing it.
上帝啊...
God...
上帝不会独自做任何事。
God doesn't do anything alone.
是弟子选择了他的师父。
It's the disciple who chooses his master.
我什么都不会写。
I can't write anything.
谁告诉你这很容易的？
Who told you it would be easy?
这样一个人躺下不起来。
That way a man lies down and rises not.
直到天堂不复存在，他们都不会醒来的。
Till the Heavens be no more, they shall not awake.
如果一个人死了，他还能再活吗？
If a man dies, shall he live again?
我挣扎的每一天，都会等待。
All the days of my struggle, I will wait.
- 佩德罗，去和他谈谈。  -  没什么好谈的。
- Pedro, go talk to him.      -  There's nothing to talk about.
安静。
Quiet.
我们可以把打字机给他。
We could give him the typewriter.
你疯了吗? 求你了！
Are you crazy? Please!
佩德罗。
Pedro.
我有钢琴，但我不是钢琴家。
I have a piano, and I'm not a pianist.
他想写，就让他写吧。
He wants to write, let him write.
以圣父、圣子、圣灵之名。
In the name of the Father, the Son and the Holy Spirit.
我说过我爱你吗？
Have I told you I love you?
不，你今天什么都没说。
No, you haven't said anything today.
那是什么？
What's that?
把那个给我。
Give me that.
这是什么意思？
What's this meaning of this?
我需要写我的书。
I need to write my book.
你需要讲述个故事。
You need a story to tell.
你疯了。
You're crazy.
如果我疯了，那会怎么样呢？
What if I am?
那又怎样？
So what?
阿姆斯特丹，20世纪80年代
AMSTERDAM, 1980s
我得过去一趟。
I have to go over there.
- 你好	 	-你好
- Hello. 	- Hello.
- 你为什么跟踪我?	                     - 是你跟踪我。
- Why are you following me?      -  You came after me.
是弟子选择了他的师父。
It's the disciple who chooses his master.
凭着对 RAM 的爱和力量，
By the power and by the love of RAM,
我邀请你成为秩序的一部分。
I invite you to become part of the order.
什么秩序？
What order?
“R”代表严格，“ A”代表感情,
‟R” as in rigor, ‟A” as in affection,
“M”是仁慈的意思。
‟M” as in mercy.
天主教会内部的一个小团体
A small order within the Catholic Church
帮助你理解这个世界的象征性语言。
that helps you to understand the symbolic language of the world.
重要的是要密切关注自己的命运和道路。
The important thing is to pay close attention to your destiny and your path.
学习你需要学习的一切
Learn everything you need to learn
才能配得上这把交给你的光之剑。
to merit the sword of light that will be entrusted to you.
剑是 RAM 的爱和力量的象征
The sword is a symbol of the love and power of RAM
只有你准备好了，它才是你的。
and it will only be yours when you are ready.
在 RAM 的神圣形象出现之前,
Before the sacred image of RAM,
用你的双手触摸生命的话语...
touch with your hands the word of life...
你会得到这样的力量
and you'll receive such power
你会亲眼目睹它对地球的影响。
that you'll witness its effects to the very ends of the earth.
圣地亚哥之路，20世纪80年代
CAMINO DE SANTIAGO, 1980s
愿使徒圣雅各与你同行，
May St. James, the apostle, travel with you
给你看你唯一应该找到的东西。
and show you the only thing you're supposed to find.
不要走得太慢或太快,
Do not walk the road too slow or too fast,
但一定要遵循路线的规律和需要。
but always follow the laws and needs of the route.
答应我，你会服从你的主人。
Promise you will obey your master.
我保证。
I promise.
愿使徒圣詹姆斯保佑你。
May St. James, the apostle, bless you.
愿上帝和圣母玛利亚日夜与你同在。
And may God and the Virgin Mary be with you day and night.
阿门。
Amen.
去吧，还有其他人在等我。
Now go. I have other people waiting.
谢谢你。
Thank you.
当你在路上的时候,
When you're on the road,
记住旅行是学习的最好方式，
remember that traveling is the best way to learn
每一次旅行都是一次冒险。
and that every journey is an adventure.
学会与神秘同在。
Learn to live with mystery.
即使你很累或者很痛苦，也要坚持走下去，边走边微笑。
Keep going even if you're tired or in pain, smile while walking.
永远记住，相信生命是一个奇迹的愿望
And always remember that the desire to believe in life as a miracle
是让奇迹发生的原因。
is what allows miracles to happen.
里约热内卢，20世纪60年代
RIO DE JANEIRO, 1960s
朝圣者，你的手伤得太重了,
Good pilgrim, you do wrong your hand too much,
这种礼貌的奉献表现在这里。
which mannerly devotion shows in this.
因为圣徒的手是圣骑士的手触摸的，
For saints have hands that paladins' hands do touch
手掌对手掌是圣洁的手掌之吻。
and palm to palm is holy palmers' kiss.
安娜，想出去走走吗？
Ana, want to go for a walk?
真的吗，安娜，他可是派对上最丑最奇怪的男孩！
Really, Ana? The ugliest and weirdest-looking boy at the party!
妈妈。
Mom.
对不起。
Sorry.
我父母离开了。
My parents are away.
我想知道你们谁会开车。
I want to know if any of you can drive.
保罗，那里好像有警察。
Paulo, I think it's the police.
那是什么？
What's that?
快开，保罗!  我想你撞死了那个男孩了。
Go, Paulo! I think you killed the boy.
再也没有零用钱了，再也不能参加派对了。
No more allowance, no more parties.
现在你得去工作了。
Now you have to work.
如果晚上超过11点，
And if it's later than 11:00 p.m.,
就不许踏进家里半步。
you won't set foot in our house again.
你不能这样对我。
You can't do this to me.
晚上11点，没得商量。
11:00 p.m. and that's it.
不管你赚多少钱,
And whatever money you earn,
都要去偿还我在那孩子身上花的每一分钱。
will go to pay back every cent that I spend on that boy.
再也没有打字机了。
And no more typewriter.
嗨，怎么了？
Hi. What's up?
- 我想和阿尔塞乌·诺盖拉谈谈。        - 他在上面。
- I'd like to talk to Alceu Nogueira.     - Up there.
我是佩德罗·  柯艾略的儿子。
I'm Pedro Coelho's son.
我准备开始工作了。
I'm ready to start.
我的办公室在哪里？
Where is my office?
你怎么了，保罗，你还好吗？
What's gotten into you, Paulo? Are you all right?
我好极了！
I'm just great!
可怜的司机！
Poor driver, Paulo!
发生什么事了？
What's going on?
别担心，莫妮卡，我们马上就到。
Don't worry, Monica. We're on our way.
两小时内到。
I'll be there in less than two hours.
你的派对很棒，你吓到我了。
Your party is great. You scared me.
我担心...
I was afraid...
克里斯，如果这是个征兆呢，那会怎么样呢?
What if it was a sign, Chris?
别担心，我们很快就会回来的。
Don't worry. It'll be back soon.
不是信号，而是征兆。
Not the signal, but a sign.
不要多想。
Don't even think about it.
这是你的派对。
It's your party.
大家都在等你。
Everyone's waiting for you.
《牧羊少年奇幻之旅》，25周年纪念
THE ALCHEMIST，25th ANNIVERSARY
克里斯，看看里面有没有地图。
Chris, see if there's a map in there.
没有。
No.
我想我们以前来过这里。
I think we've been here before.
等一下，保罗。
Just a second, Paulo.
你不来吗？
You're not coming?
你要去哪里?
Where are you going?
如果我知道，我会告诉你的。
If I knew, I'd tell you.
但我会找到办法的。
But I'll get somewhere.
我知道你会的。
I know you will.
保罗，你在干什么？
Paulo, what are you doing?
圣地亚哥之路，2013年
CAMINO DE SANTIAGO, 2013
我的鞋。
My shoe.
少即是多
LESS IS MORE
把你带不动的重物留在这里
LEAVE ALL THE WEIGHT YOU CANNOT CARRY HERE
- 你没事吧?                   - 我没事。
- Are you all right?	       - Yes, I am.
哦，天哪，真的是他吗？
Oh, my God, is it really you？
当然是他。
Of course he is.
真是一个耻辱。
It's a shame.
但从近处看，没有人是他们看起来的样子。
But from up close, no one is whom they seem to be.
他和我都一样，
He's all just like me,
总是想回到同一个地方。
always wanting to come back to the same place.
你知道这次你要找什么吗？
Do you know what you're looking for this time?
还不知道，但我肯定能找到。
Not yet. But I'm sure I'll find it.
每个人都尽可能讲述自己的故事。
Everybody tells their story as best they can.
或者以他们想要的方式讲述。
Or the way they want to.
如果我们能改变生命，
Life is only really worth it
它才真正值得。
if we can change it.
只是为了客厅。
Just for the living room.
- 你什么都没说                      -儿子。
- You never said anything. 	- Son.
过来和我们一起吃晚饭，打电话给你姐姐。
Come and eat dinner with us. Call your sister.
我不饿。
I'm not hungry.
需要我给你留点吃的，
Do you want me to save you some food
等你回来吗？
for when you come back?
不用了，谢谢。
No, thanks.
晚上11点，我就会锁门，晚回来的话你就进不来了。
At 11:00, I lock the doors and you can't come in.
我20岁了，我有自己的生活，我想做什么就做什么。
I'm 20 years old. It's my life. I'll do as I like.
除非我帮你付账单。
Not while I pay your bills.
你满脑子想的都是这个。
That's all you think about.
太好了！
Far out!
什么，付账单和赚钱吗？
What, paying bills and making money?
真正离谱的是
What's really far out is
你根本不在乎，孩子。
that you don't care about that, kid.
在乎什么？
What for?
就像你那样抛弃我的生活吗？
To throw my life away, like you did with yours?
省钱建那个可笑的房子吗？
Saving money to build this ridiculous house?
资本家! 雇佣兵！
Capitalist! Mercenary!
那你是什么? 你是共产主义者吗？
And what are you? Are you a communist?
- 这有什么不对吗?	                      - 亲爱的上帝...
- And what's wrong with that?    -  Dear God...
这个国家的总统是个将军。
The president of this country is a general.
你知道军事独裁是什么吗?   知道吗？
Do you know what a military dictatorship is? Do you?
你知道将军们怎么对付共产党吗？
Do you know what generals do with communists?
我能忍受你，我能忍受任何事。
I've put up with you. I can put up with anything.
我的上帝...
My God...
上帝是你忘恩负义的见证人。
God is a witness of your ungratefulness.
你会得到你应得的。
You'll get what you deserve.
- 我保证你会的。					- 希望如此。
- I promise you will.                - I hope so.
出去。
Get out.
滚！
Go!
走开。
Go away.
最后一步，1，2，3，停。
Last move. 1, 2, 3, stop.
恭喜你们，真的很棒。
Congratulations, guys. It was really good.
我觉得你最后应该多走动走动。
I think you should move around a little more in the end.
卡洛斯，我想和你谈谈。
Carlos, I'd like to talk to you.
我以为你抛弃我们了。
I thought you'd abandoned us.
- 我工作很忙。             - 新工作吗？
- I was working a lot.    -  New job?
是新剧本。
New play.
真的吗，让我看看。
Really? Let me see it.
- 安娜，我们要开始了。       - 不，等一下。
- Ana, we're about to start. 	 -  No, just a second.
我们得开始排练了。
We have to start rehearsing now.
- 弗拉维奥还没来呢              - 他不会来了。
- Flavio isn't even here yet. 	- He's not coming.
也许那个瘦子可以扮演他的角色。
Maybe the skinny guy can play his role.
- 不要啦。            - 他扮小丑一定很好看。
- Of course not. 	  -  He'll look great as a clown.
别说了，我朋友是来看我的。
Stop it! My friend's here to visit me...
我可以扮小丑。
I can play the clown.
我想扮演。
I want to do it.
- 你是认真的吗？      - 是的。
- Are you serious?       - Yes, I am.
你叫什么来着？
What's your name again?
- 马可            - 马可
- Marco         -  Marco
我也是演员，我没告诉过你吗？
I'm an actor too. Haven't I told you?
没有。
No.
我来扮小丑。
I'll play the clown.
当春天的土豆发芽的时候,
When the spring potato sprouts,
它就会蔓延到整个地面。
it spreads all over the ground.
当小女孩睡着的时候,
When the little girl sleeps,
她把手放在心上。
she puts her hand on her heart.
现在这个问题不会停止。
Now the question that won't stop.
- 谁想要巧克力?                   - 我要！
- Who wants a chocolate?     - I do!
我听不见哦。
I can't hear you.
我要！
I do!
太好了！
All right!
安东尼奥·布兰科（António Branco，生于1957年）葡萄牙著名小丑，饰演Batatinha(小土豆)
小土豆! 小土豆！
Batatinha! Batatinha!
- 你想留在这里吗?                   - 干杯。
- Do you want to stay here?     - A toast.
我受够你了。
I'm sick and tired of you.
- 我要走了                - 走吧。
- I'm out of here.      - Go ahead.
来吧，让我们为巴西舞台上
Well, let's make a toast to the best clown
有史以来最好的小丑干杯。
the Brazilian stage has ever seen.
小土豆！
Batatinha!
- 谢谢你帮我们                  - 谢谢。
- Thanks for helping us.     - Thank you.
干杯！
A toast!
安娜，我得回家了。
Ana, I have to go home.
不要啦。
No.
你是认真的吗？
Are you serious?
小土豆变成南瓜了吗？
Is Batatinha turning into a pumpkin?
差不多吧。
More or less.
再待一会儿，求你了。
Stay a little longer. Please.
求你了，再待一会儿。
Please. Just a little longer.
求你了，留下吧。
Please. Stay.
留下吧。
Stay.
- 再待一会儿                  -  好的，再待一会儿。
- Just a little longer.        -  Okay, just a little longer.
我回来了！
I'm home!
佩德罗！
Pedro!
你这该死的资本家！
You damn capitalist!
雇佣兵！
Mercenary!
- 你这个混蛋!       - 我去开门吧。
- You bastard!      - Do something.
蠢货。
Dumb-ass.
去你的！
Damn you!
- 他翻进门了          - 混蛋！
- He's in.                  - Asshole!
那孩子必须学会尊重我们的规矩。
That boy must learn to respect our rules.
邻居会怎么想？
What about the neighbors?
笨蛋！
Stupid!
别担心，保罗。
Don't worry, Paulo.
会没事的。
It will be all right.
这是一种新疗法,
It's a new treatment,
最现代的那种。
the most modern one there is.
没有痛苦，没有折磨。
No pain, no suffering.
相信我，孩子。
Trust me, boy.
圣地亚哥之路，20世纪80年代
CAMINO DE SANTIAGO, 1980s
克里斯！
Chris!
每当一个有害的想法在你脑海中闪过时，
Whenever a harmful thought crosses your mind
就把你的食指指甲推到你的拇指根部，
push the nail of your index finger into the base of your thumb
直到你感到剧烈的疼痛。
until you feel intense pain.
把注意力集中在痛苦上。
Concentrate on the pain.
它将反映在物质领域
It will reflect in the physical realm
和你在精神世界里感受到的痛苦一样。
the same pain you feel in the spiritual realm.
只有当这种想法离开你的头脑时才能释放压力。
Only relieve the pressure when that thought departs your mind.
里约热内卢，20世纪60年代
RIO DE JANEIRO, 1960s
你好。
Hello.
这么说这孩子情绪不稳定喽？
So the boy is unstable?
- 是的。		-不是。
- Yes. 			- No.
是还是不是？
Yes or no?
不是。
No.
他没有不稳定。
He's not unstable.
他正在接受治疗。
He's currently undergoing treatment.
没什么大不了的，很快就好。
Nothing serious, it's something quick.
保罗是个好孩子。
Paulo is a good person.
我明白，第二次
I see, a good person
被送进精神病院的好孩子。
who's been institutionalized for the second time.
是的。
Yes.
我儿子是个好人,
My son is a good person,
但他患有一定程度的
but he suffers from a certain degree of
精神分裂症和妄想症。
schizophrenia and paranoia.
- 佩德罗	      - 医生认为..
- Pedro. 	      - And the doctors think that—
佩德罗！
Pedro!
我知道了。
I got it.
- 他两天前失踪了?				               - 是的。
- He disappeared two days ago? 	   -  Right.
快三天了。
Almost three days.
医院、停尸房都找过。
Hospitals, morgues.
我们去过所有地方。
We've been everywhere.
我们不知道该怎么办。
We don't know what to do.
你必须保持冷静，佩德罗。
You have to stay calm, Pedro.
保罗是我的孙子，他想住多久就住多久。
Paulo is my grandson and he can stay as long as he likes.
保罗，我们只想确保你没事。
Paulo, we just want to make sure you're okay.
好吗？
All right?
所以我要搬去和他们一起住。
So I'm moving in with them.
这样对大家都好，不是吗？
Yeah, it will be good for everybody, won't it?
《缺席的发明家》
‟THE ABSENT INVENTOR”
保罗· 柯艾略的戏剧作品
A PLAY BY PAULO COELHO DE SOUZA
在后面的一个小房间里，女巫和雨神相遇了。
In a small room in the back, the witch and the rain god meet.
人类的命运被解读和改变。
Humanity's fate is read and changed.
最伟大的事情是在几秒钟内
The greatest things are built and undone
建立和撤销的,
in a matter of seconds,
而女巫的声音从未停止。
and the voice of the witch never stops.
永不停止。
It never stops.
看看这个，佩德罗。
Look at this, Pedro.
我们的小伙子很受欢迎。
Our boy is a big hit.
嗨，亲爱的，你太棒了。
Hi, honey. You kicked ass.
- 嗨，儿子。	 - 嗨，妈妈。
- Hi, son. 	     -  Hi, Mom.
-  恭喜				                 - 谢谢。
-  Congratulations. 	     - Thanks.
- 你爸爸也来了，佩德罗			- 抱歉。
- Your dad is here too. Pedro. 	- Excuse me.
那又怎样？
So?
你喜欢吗？
Did you like it?
我知道你会的。
I knew you would.
你在哭吗? 为什么? 你不高兴吗？
Are you crying? Why? Aren't you happy?
好像你不喜欢掌声似的。
As if you didn't like the applause.
我不喜欢这出戏。
I don't like the play.
我等会回来。
I'll be back.
“你这个拖延之人，
‟You who procrastinate
不要想着死亡的到来,
and think not of death's arrival,
献身于生活中的无用之物。“
dedicating yourself to the useless things in life.”
“无意识地，你挥霍...
‟Improvidently, you squander...
你最好的机会。
your greatest opportunity.
幻想破灭，这就是你的目标。
Disillusioned, this will certainly be your purpose.
现在你又空手而归了”。
Now that you're returning empty-handed from life.”
“但是所有的圣人和好人,
‟But all saints and good men,
当他们看到死亡的使者,
when they see the messengers of death,
他们不会不假思索地行动。
they don't act without thinking.
相反，他们听从高尚的教义所言。
Instead they listen to what the noble doctrine says.
在这个拥抱中，它感到恐惧,
And it's in this embrace, frightened,
出生和死亡的肥沃源头。
that the fertile source of birth and death comes in.
他们从拥抱中解脱出来
And they release themselves from the embrace
正在熄灭
extinguishing
生与死。
birth and death.
他们安全而快乐。”
They are safe and happy.”
摆脱这种转瞬即逝的景象。
‟Free from this whole fleeting spectacle.
远离所有的罪恶，恐惧和道路,
From all sins and fears and paths,
他们会克服所有的痛苦”
你愿意娶我吗？
Do you want to marry me?
你叫什么名字？
What's your name?
保罗。
Paulo.
- 你呢?	              - 路易莎。
- And yours?     - Luiza.
像我这么丑的人怎么可能
How can an ugly guy like me
相信如此美丽的女人的爱呢？
believe in the love of such a beautiful woman?
你想让我证明吗？
Do you want me to prove it?
你相信上帝吗？
Do you believe in God?
相信上帝吗？
In God?
祂以前经常吓唬我。
He used to scare me.
但现在...
But now...
现在？
Now?
祂是否存在我已不再关心了。
Whether or not He exists is not my problem anymore.
- 我放弃了。   -不，千万不要！
- I give up.        - No, don't!
别破坏气氛，我觉得会成功的。
Don't ruin it. I feel it's going to work.
我以为你不信上帝。
I thought you didn't believe in God.
如果上帝真的存在，祂肯定在做别的事。
If God exists, he's doing something else.
但我必须相信我们自己的力量。
But I have to believe in our power.
- 如果这个烟灰缸碎了...		  - 不玩了，保罗！
- If this ashtray breaks...         - Enough, Paulo!
我们睡觉吧。
Let's go to sleep.
看到了吗，齐扎，成功了！
See, Ziza? It worked!
帮我捡一下！
Help me!
你看到发生什么事了吗？
Did you see what happened?
- 是的，烟灰缸掉了		      - 不。
- Yes, the ashtray fell.          - No.
仔细听听。
Pay attention.
保罗，这太荒谬了
Paulo, this is ridiculous.
不，这是心灵的力量。
No, it's the power of the mind.
我们太有才了，无所不能。
It's genius! We can do anything.
一切都在这儿！
It's all here!
太有才了！
It's genius!
我们是天才！
Genius!
符号的语言
The language of signs
总是随时准备揭露眼睛看不到的东西。
is always ready to reveal what the eyes can't see.
上帝在这个世界上写下了每个人必须走的路。
God has written in this world the path each person must take.
你只需要读祂为你写的东西。
You only have to read what He has written for you.
1974年3月15日。
March 15th, 1974.
在巴西利亚，抵达国会的是
In Brasília, arriving at Congress,
埃内斯托·盖泽尔将军和阿达尔维托·杜斯·桑托斯，
are General Ernesto Geisel and Adalberto Pereira dos Santos,
参加他们的总统和副总统就职典礼。
for their inauguration as president and vice-president.
选举团选出的新统治者
The new rulers elected by the electoral college
致力于维护、保护和遵守宪法,
are committed to maintain, protect and obey the Constitution,
以及巴西的完整和独立。
the integrity and independence of Brazil.
参议员保罗. 托雷斯主持的会议结束时ー
As the session presided over by Senator Paulo Torres ended—
作为交换，他们会给我们健康和内心的平静。
In exchange they'll give us health and peace of mind.
这就是它的用途吗？
And is that what it's for?
我们没有任何需求和欲望。
We don't have any needs or desires.
这是个真正的、
It's a real Eden,
充满归属和爱的伊甸园。
belonging and loving.
没有需求或欲望吗？
No needs or desires?
我们不是为此而生的。
We weren't made for that.
没有雄心壮志和超越自我的愿望，人类就会陷入困境。
Man gets stuck without ambition and desire to be more than he is.
我们已经得到我们想要的了。
We have what we want.
除了挑战。
Except the challenge.
你不明白，吉姆，但你会明白的,
You don't understand, Jim, but you will,
这是迟早的事。
sooner or later.
请加入我们。
Join us, please.
吉扎，我能向你借点钱吗？
Ziza, can I borrow some money from you?
我要做我自己的杂志。
I'm going to make my own magazine.
心灵感应
TELEPATHY
奥古斯托 · 菲格雷多的一篇文章
AN ARTICLE BY AUGUSTO FIGUEIREDO
旅行
THE TRIP
魔法师的阿莱斯特·克劳利
THE MAGUS ALEISTER CROWLEY
请进。
Come in.
奥古斯托·菲格雷多在吗？
Augusto Figueiredo?
不，奥古斯托·菲格雷多不在这里。
No, Augusto Figueiredo isn't here.
需要帮忙吗？
Can I help you?
不，我要见他本人，我等等吧。
No, it's with him personally, I will wait.
我马上回来。
I'll be right back.
爷爷，过来。
Grandpa, come here.
我敢肯定他是个警察。
I'm sure he's a cop.
- 那又怎样?	     - 他要把我带走。
- So?		             - He's going to take me.
你没那么重要。
You're not that important.
替我亲一下吉扎。
Give Ziza a kiss for me.
如果我死了，告诉她，我是爱她而死的。
And if I die, tell her I died loving her.
- 告诉她...				   - 走吧。
- And tell her that...	- Go on.
- 宇宙在密谋...					           - 去吧。
- That the universe conspires...	   - Just go there.
听着。
Listen.
奥古斯托·菲格雷多并不存在。
Augusto Figueiredo doesn't exist.
杂志的所有文章都是我写的。
I write all the material for the magazine.
是你写了那些关于飞碟的东西吗？
You're the one who writes those far out things about flying saucers?
是的，所有东西都是我写的。
Yes, all of them.
我的名字是保罗· 柯艾略
My name is Paulo Coelho de Souza.
如果你是来逮捕我的，来吧，抓我吧。
If you're here to arrest me, go on, take me.
逮捕你，带你去哪？
Arrest you? And take you where?
我想跟你谈谈。
I want to talk to you.
朋友，我是劳尔· 塞克萨斯。
I'm Raul Seixas, my friend.
非常荣幸认识你。
It's a great pleasure.
我对 UFO 感兴趣。
I'm interested in ufology.
听着,
But listen,
你觉得有多少人会看你的杂志？
how many people do you think read your magazine?
很多，怎么了？
Many, why?
我有些想法。
I have some ideas.
我是制片人， CBS唱片公司的经理。
I'm a producer, manager at CBS, the record label.
你知道CBS，对吧？
You know it, right?
我来这里，
The thing is,
是想考虑和你合作音乐。
I'm thinking about making a music partnership.
我觉得很有意思。
I think it's interesting.
你觉得怎么样？
What do you think?
西装革履，太正式了。
Suit and tie? It's so square.
这跟我们没关系！
It has nothing to do with us!
这不正点。
It's not square.
这家伙...
This guy is...
他...
He...
我不知道他想干嘛。
I don't know what he is.
你真的认为他会在杂志上登广告吗？
Do you really think he'll put ads in the magazine?
我试试看。
I'll try.
谁知道呢，也许音乐这件事会成功。
Who knows, maybe the music thing will work out.
也许会...
Maybe it will...
但是唱片公司总裁呢？
but record label executive?
他有点怪。
He's a bit weird.
他说的那些话...
The things he says...
我忘不了我在电视上看到的内容。
And I can't forget that thing I saw on TV.
那是史波克（星际迷航角色）说的。
That thing Spock said.
你在开玩笑吗，保罗？
Are you kidding, Paulo?
这是个征兆，我很确定。
It's a sign, I'm sure of it.
看看你怎么想，你知道该怎么做。
See what you think of it. You know what to do.
让我看看...
Let me see...
人的自由就是宇宙的正义。
The freedom of man is the justice of the universe.
当阿尔 · 卡彭...
When Al Capone...
- 阿尔 · 卡彭		- 我知道。
- Al Capone. 		- I know.
“宇宙的正义?”
‟The justice of the universe”?
保利尼奥，这真是太正点了!
Paulinho, this is so square!
我觉得不是这样的。
I don't think that's the way.
我告诉过你，我不会写歌。
I told you I don't know how to write songs.
- 别这么说			     - 我就是这么写的。
- Don't say that. 	    - That's how I write.
这不可行。
No way.
歌曲是为了传递信息，你不需要花哨。
To get a message across, you don't need to be fancy.
你可以简单些，用词必须简单。
You can keep it simple. You must keep it simple.
那要怎么做呢？
But how?
简单，直接，向前迈进。
Simple, direct, forward.
我明白了，比如:
I get it, something like:
嘿，阿尔·卡彭，看看你是否弄明白了。
Hey, Al Capone, see if you get it straight.
就是这样！
That's it!
你得要领了！
You got it!
嘿，阿尔·卡彭，看看你是否弄明白了。
Hey, Al Capone, see if you get it straight.
听着。
Listen.
嘿，阿尔·卡彭，看看你是否弄明白了。
Hey, Al Capone, see if you get it straight.
- 明白了吗？    - 明白了。
- Got it?	          - I got it.
- 让我试试		- 更直接一点。
- Let me try. 	- More direct.
稍后我想和你谈谈
Later I want to talk to you about
CBS 投资我杂志的事。
CBS investing in my magazine.
算了吧，音乐才是真正的东西。
Forget about that, music is the real thing.
音乐触及人们的灵魂。
It's music that reaches people's souls.
但杂志也...
But the magazine also...
问题是，你想与世界对话。
The thing is, you want to talk to the world.
你有很多话要说，不是吗？
You have a lot to say, don't you?
你想成为比你自己更强大的人，对吗？
You want to be bigger than you are, right?
那么...
So...
来，跟我一起，兄弟。
Come with me, brother.
嘿，阿尔·卡彭，看看你是否弄明白了。
Hey, Al Capone, see if you get it straight.
照现在的情况...
The way things are going
伙计,继续...
Man...
芝加哥跟不上你的脚步
Chicago won't keep up with you.
芝加哥跟不上！
Chicago won't keep up!
- 哇，保利尼奥!		- 简单多了。
- Wow, Paulinho!	- It's simpler.
你真是个天才! 你彻底明白了！
You're a genius! You got it all!
芝加哥跟不上！
Chicago won't keep up!
嘿，阿尔· 卡彭，看看你能不能治好自己。
Hey, Al Capone, see if you fix yourself.
他们知道了你在国税局的欺诈行为。
They know about your fraud with the IRS.
嘿，凯撒大帝，别去参议院。
Hey, Julius Caesar, don't go to the Senate.
他们知道了你控制国家的阴谋。
They know about your plot to control the State.
嘿，兰皮昂，离开这里。
Hey, Lampião, take a step out of here.
他们要把你的头拿去展览。
They're going to the fair putting your head on exhibit.
嘿，阿尔·卡彭，看看你是否弄明白了。
Hey, Al Capone, see if you get straight.
照现在的情况，芝加哥跟不上。
The way things are going, man, Chicago won't keep up.
我是占星家。
I'm an astrologer.
你一定要相信我。
You must believe in me.
我是占星家。
I'm an astrologer.
我对历史了如指掌。
And I know history from beginning to end.
劳尔，劳尔，劳尔！
Raul! Raul! Raul!
圣地亚哥之路，20世纪80年代
CAMINO DE SANTIAGO, 1980s
躺在地上，放松。
Lie down on the ground and relax.
双手交叉放在胸前，
Cross your hands over your chest
就像你已经死了一样。
as if you were dead.
想象一下你葬礼的每个细节，
Picture every detail of your funeral
就好像明天就要举行一样。
as if it were to happen tomorrow.
唯一的区别就是。
The only difference is
你被活埋了。
that you are being buried alive.
随着时间的流逝,
As history develops,
人们走进教堂，走向坟墓,
the Church, the walk towards the grave,
棺材降落墓地,
the descent of the coffin,
坟墓里的虫子叮咬你...
the worms in the tomb...
慢慢地伸展你的肌肉，用力动动身子,
You slowly stretch your muscles in an effort to move,
但你动不了。
but you can't move.
我采访过这些人，他们太棒了！
I had an interview with these guys. They're amazing!
就是这条路，劳尔。
This is the way, Raul.
我们需要更有力的歌词。
We need more powerful stuff.
他们太不可思议了，劳尔。
They're incredible, Raul.
克劳力，克劳力是谁？
Crowley? Who is Crowley?
律法之书，你想怎么做就怎么做。
The Book of the Law. Do what you want.
好吧，法律就是这样。
All right. It's all about the law.
- 听我说		           - 我在听
- Listen to me.       - I'm listening.
我跟那家伙聊了两个小时。
I spoke to that guy for two hours.
- 有烟吗?			             - 听我说！
- Got a cigarette?	     - Listen to me!
- 我在听			    - 该死！
- I'm listening. 	- Damn!
给我根烟。
Give me a cigarette.
我跟他聊了两个小时。
I spoke to him for two hours.
他会告诉我们的。
And he'll talk to us.
采访克劳力的唯一继承人
INTERVIEW WITH CROWLEY'S ONLY HEIR
保罗，这是很重要的事。
Paulo, this is heavy duty stuff.
但不是我们该关心的事。
This isn't our thing.
你疯了吗？
Are you crazy?
我知道我在说什么吗？！
I know what I'm talking about.
你不是说我们会改变世界吗？
Didn't you say we would change the world?
要和人们的灵魂对话吗？！
Talk to people's souls?
我说过要做音乐，音乐。
I talked about making music. Music.
通过音乐感动人们的灵魂。
Touching people's souls through music.
这完全是另一码事。
It's another thing entirely.
你说过我们会大受欢迎的。
You said we'd be a big hit.
这不正是我们想要的吗？
Isn't it what we want?
我们想要，如果我想要，你也想要
We want it, and if I want it and you want it—
我是认真的。
I mean it.
不行，我不干了。
No way, I'm out of this.
跟我一起，兄弟。
Come with me, brother.
魔法誓言是一种纽带。
A magic oath is a link...
而且必须是真正意志的主张...
And it must be the assertion of true will...
魔法誓言是一种
A magic oath is a link
在人类意识和神性意识之间的纽带。
between human consciousness and divine consciousness.
是一个纽带...
It is a link...
- 你准备好了吗?		- 是的，我准备好了。
- Are you ready?	    - Yes, I am.
是的。
Yes.
凭借真理的力量,
By the power of the truth,
我活着的时候征服了宇宙。
I, while living, have conquered the universe.
重复一遍。
Repeat it.
凭借真理的力量,
By the power of the truth,
我活着的时候征服了宇宙。
I, while living, have conquered the universe.
写下来。
Write it down.
万岁
Long live
另类社会万岁！
Long live alternative society!
万岁
Long live
另类社会万岁！
Long live alternative society!
吉扎！
Ziza!
这是什么？
What is it?
- 我做不到			- 什么？
- I can't do this. 	- What?
- 过来帮我这个忙			        - 做什么？
- Come and do this for me. 	- Do what?
过来。
Come here.
另类社会万岁！
Long live alternative society!
和你在一起，我亲爱的搭档,
With you, my dear partner,
我的兄弟,
my brother,
唐·保罗· 柯艾略！
Dom Paulo Coelho!
万岁！
Long live!
另类社会万岁！
Long live alternative society!
万岁！
Long live!
另类社会万岁！
Long live alternative society!
万岁！
Long live!
每个男人，每个女人，都是明星。
Every man and every woman is a star.
每个人都有权利去想他想做的事情。
Every man has the right to think whatever he wants.
他有权说任何他想说的话。
He has the right to say whatever he wants.
做他想做的任何事情。
And do whatever he wants.
万岁！
Long live!
另类社会万岁！
Long live alternative society!
如果我想，你也想，
If I want and you want
戴着帽子洗澡
To take a shower wearing a hat
或者等圣诞老人
Or to wait for Santa Claus
或者讨论卡洛斯·加德尔
Or to discuss Carlos Gardel
那就去吧！
Then go!
做你想做的事，因为这是合法的。
Do whatever you want because it's within the law.
合法的!
The law.
万岁！
Long live!
另类社会万岁！
Long live alternative society!
万岁！
Long live!
另类社会万岁！
Long live alternative society!
现在播放一首名为《一万个阿诺斯》的歌曲,
And now the song called Eu Nasci Há 10,000 Anos Atrás,
由保罗· 柯艾略和劳尔·塞克萨斯演唱的热门歌曲。
a hit by Paulo Coelho and Raul Seixas, performed by Raul Seixas.
佩德罗，你经常提到
Pedro, you often mention
你总是抱怨孤独，
you're always complaining about solitude,
你是用铁和火铸成的，佩德罗。
you were made with iron and with fire, Pedro.
可惜你不知道
Too bad you don't know it
你每天都去上班
You go to work every day
不知道是好是坏
Not knowing whether it's good or bad
你想哭的时候就去洗手间
When you want to cry you go to the bathroom
佩德罗，事情不应该是这样的
Pedro, that's not how things should be
搞什么鬼？
What the hell?
别动！
Stay still!
这是什么鬼东西？
What is this crap here?
这是我和劳尔·塞克萨斯一起做的唱片。
It's a record I made with Raul Seixas.
我知道这是唱片。
I know it's a record.
但是“ Krig-ha，Bandolo”是什么意思呢？
But what does ‟Krig-ha, Bandolo” mean?
意思是“小心，敌人就在附近”
It means ‟Watch out, the enemy's near.”
什么敌人，政府吗？
What enemy? The government?
什么政府? 跟这没关系。
What government? It has nothing to do with it.
- 我们的敌人是别的东西。		- 是谁？
- Our enemy is something else. 	- Who?
非洲的狮子。
The lions in Africa.
上面写着，用恩东戈王国的语言写的。
It says there, in the language spoken in the Kingdom of Ndongo.
开什么玩笑，我们看起来像小丑吗？
Are you kidding me? Do we look like clowns to you?
不，先生，我说的是实话。
No, sir. I'm telling you the truth.
- 我们又在旅行了，先生			-什么样的旅行？
- We're on another trip, sir. 	    - What kind of ‟trip”?
我们想结束无聊。
We want to put an end to boredom.
无聊的世界。
Boredom in the world.
-  无聊？	             - 是的。
- Boredom?          - Yes.
我们喜欢魔法，你不会明白的。
And we're into magic. You wouldn't understand.
是的，我真的不知道。
No, I really don't.
普利尼奥，打开机器,
Plinio, turn on the machine,
这样我们就可以把我们朋友的想法理顺。
so that we can put our friend's ideas in order.
你要折磨我吗，先生？
Are you going to torture me, sir?
- 不，我不会的       - 再来一遍吗，先生？
- No, I'm not. 	         - Again, sir?
闭嘴，你这个白痴！
Shut up, you idiot!
他妈的闭嘴！
Shut the fuck up!
我疯了，先生，继续折磨我吧。
I'm crazy, sir. Go ahead and torture me.
来吧，普利尼奥，看看我的档案，黑名单。
Go ahead, Plinio. Take a look at my file, the black list.
这就证实了这一点。“疯子，疯子!”
That will confirm it. ‟Crazy, lunatic!”
我进过精神病院，先生。
I was in a mental institution, sir.
- 真的吗？	     - 真的。
- Really? 	         - Really.
- 我接受过电击治疗		 	- 电击治疗？
- I had shock treatment. 	- Shock treatment?
- 是的，你知道那是什么吗?			     -是的，我知道。
- Yes. Do you know what that is?	     - Yes, I do.
你喜欢休克疗法吗？
Do you like shock treatment?
是的，感觉很好。
Yes, I do. It feels really good.
但这不是折磨。
But it isn't torture.
- 不是吗?		-不是。
- Isn't it?		- No.
休克治疗不是折磨。
Shock treatment isn't torture.
休克治疗很好。
Shock treatment is just great.
对你来说什么是折磨？
What is torture for you?
对我来说，折磨就是抽血。
Torture is drawing blood.
- 你喜欢血，对吧?				      - 我喜欢。
- You like blood, don't you?	  - I love it.
是吗？
Do you?
狗娘养的！
Son of a bitch!
真不敢相信！
I can't believe it!
他是个彻头彻尾的疯子，快把他带走。
He's a total lunatic. Get him out of here.
我应该切掉一根手指吗？
Should I cut off a finger?
不! 滚出去，你这个疯子！
No! Get out of here, you crazy asshole!
没有仇恨，没有宽恕
NO HATRED AND NO FORGIVENESS
他要去纽约吗？
He's going to New York City?
他是我的搭档。
He's my partner.
叫他接电话！
Tell him to answer the phone!
让劳尔接电话！
Tell Raul to answer the phone!
告诉他。
Tell him.
对于圣塞浦路斯人来说,
For Saint Cyprian,
路西法策划了一场反对魔王的政变，夺取了政权。
Lucifer staged a coup d'etat against Beelzebub and took power.
他们之间的分歧
And the disagreements between the two of them
阻碍了地球上的邪恶500年,
impeded evil on Earth for 500 years,
已经结束的五个世纪。
Five centuries that have come to an end.
这种魔法现象，这种对魔法的突然兴趣,
This magical phenomenon, this sudden interest in magic,
在电影《驱魔人》中出现的整个事件
in this whole thing that is emerging with the movie The Exorcist
被认为是原因，而实际上是结果。
is considered the cause when it is actually the effect.
还有我刚写的那首歌“ Gita”谈到...
And the song ‟Gita,” which I just wrote, talks about...
“我刚写的”？
‟I just wrote”?
- 善与恶合二为一				        -“我刚写的”？！
- Good and evil as one thing. 	- ‟I just wrote”?!
善恶结合在一起，将上帝作为一个整体呈现出来。
Together, they bring out God as a whole in person.
当我在世界的四个角落寻找的时候。
While I've gone searching to the four corners of the world
祂终于在梦里告诉我。
It was finally in a dream that he told me.
有时候你问我：
Sometimes you ask me:
为什么我这么安静？
Why I'm so quiet?
我几乎不谈爱情。
I barely speak of love.
我不会陪在你身边，微笑着。
And I don't stay by your side, smiling.
你无时无刻不在想我。
You think of me all the time
你掏空我，耗尽我，然后离开我。
You eat me, you spit me out, you leave me.
也许你不明白。
Maybe you don't understand.
但今天我要让你看看。
But today I'll show you.
我是星星的光芒
I am the light of the stars
我是月光的颜色
I am the color of the moonlight
我就是生命中的事物
I am the things in life
我是爱的恐惧
I am the fear of loving
魔法誓言是一种纽带
A magic oath is a link
而且必须是真正意志的主张...
And it must be the assertion of true will...
它是一种纽带，
It's a link
在人类意识和神性意识之间的纽带。
between human consciousness and divine consciousness.
发生什么事了？
What's happening?
水! 水! 水！
Water! Water! Water!
过来。
Come here.
保罗。
Paulo.
进来吧。
Come in.
我喜欢 A 面。
I like the A side.
背面也不错。
But this one is good too.
我们喜欢同一张唱片。
So we like the same one.
我也有我的秘密。
I also have my secrets.
对不起，孩子。
I'm sorry, son.
你为什么现在告诉我这些？
Why are you telling me this now?
因为你是我儿子。
Because you're my son.
作为你的父亲，我真的很自豪。
And I'm really proud to be your father.
看到你在加维亚建造
It makes me proud to see
属于自己的房子，我感到很自豪。”
you building your own ‟house in Gávea.”
用我自己的方式。
In my own way.
必须用你自己的方式。
It had to be in your own way.
实际上，唱片B面的歌要好一点。
Actually, this song on the B side is a little better.
谢谢，爸爸。
Thanks, Dad.
姐姐，过来。
Sis, come here.
那边的女孩是谁？
Who's that girl over there?
克里斯，马克斯的侄女。
It's Chris, Marcos' niece.
圣地亚哥之路，20世纪80年代
CAMINO DE SANTIAGO, 1980s
点燃蜡烛，凝视火焰。
Light a candle and gaze into the flame.
把注意力集中在你最渴望的东西
Focus on what you most desire
和你要克服的挑战上。
and on the challenges to be overcome.
记住，为了正义之战，我们需要寻求帮助。
Remember that to fight the Good Fight we need help.
如果我们不能理解这一点，
If we fail to understand that,
我们将成为傲慢的战士。
we will be arrogant warriors.
最终，我们的傲慢会击败我们。
In the end, our arrogance will defeat us.
我们对自己盲目自信，
We'll be so sure of ourselves
以至于我们无法看到战场上的陷阱。
that we won't be able to see the traps in the battlefield.
一千人会倒在你身边，
A thousand may fall at your side,
一万人会倒在你右边。
and 10,000 to your right.
但你不会受到伤害。
But you will not be harmed.
邪恶和瘟疫都不会到达你的住所,
No evil nor plague shall reach your dwelling,
因为上帝会在所有的旅程中保护你。
because God will protect you in all your journeys.
朝圣
THE PILGRIMAGE
晚上好。
Good evening.
我能跟你谈谈吗？
Can I talk to you for a second?
我给大家推荐这本书。
I recommend it.
谢谢你。
Thank you.
起来啊！
Get up!
- 我哪里做错了?				       - 你为什么这么想呢？
- What am I doing wrong?	  -  Why do you think that?
因为...
Because...
我们写作是为了让人们阅读。
We write for people to read.
否则，它没有意义。
Otherwise, it doesn't make sense.
你卖了一千多本书，已经很多了。
You sold over a thousand books. It's a lot.
我知道，我知道，但是...
I know, I know, but...
我说的不是这个。
I'm not talking about that.
一切都是一回事,
Everything is one thing only
当你真心渴望某样东西时，
and when you want something,
整个宇宙都会联合起来帮助你实现 。
all the universe conspires in helping you achieve it.
保罗,
Paulo,
我是你的朋友。
I'm a friend of yours.
作为朋友，我告诉你。
And as a friend, I'll tell you this.
这本书...
This book...
这本书不好。
This book isn't good.
我读过，试着喜欢它。
I read it and I tried to like it.
我真的很想喜欢它。
I really wanted to like it.
但这次不行。
But this time it won't do.
我不能继续投资了。
I can't keep on investing in this.
听着，我想帮你。
Listen, I want to help you.
你写得很好，我在媒体有关系。
You write well, I have contacts in the press.
我是个作家。
I'm a writer.
保罗,
Paulo,
你真的认为有一天会有人
do you really think someone will someday
想读你写的东西吗？
want to read the things you write?
保持静默，观察你周围的动象。
Remain silent and observe the movement around you.
密切注意这些迹象。
Pay close attention to the signs.
每天，上帝都会赐予我们一个时刻，
Every day, God grants us a moment in which
在这个时刻，我们有可能改变
it's possible to change everything
给我们带来不快乐的一切。
that brings us unhappiness.
这个神奇的瞬间就是
This magic instant is the moment when
一个“是”或“否”的瞬间，它可以改变我们的整个存在。
a ‟yes” or a ‟no” can change our entire existence.
当你真心渴望某样东西时，
And when you want something,
整个宇宙都会联合起来帮你实现。
all the universe conspires in helping you achieve it.
《牧羊少年奇幻之旅》， 保罗· 柯艾略，1988年5月
THE ALCHEMIST, PAULO COELHO , MAY, 1988
保罗有了一位新编辑，
Paulo got a new editor
《牧羊少年奇幻之旅》于1988年首次出版。
and The Alchemist was first published in 1988.
从那以后这本书就一直排在纽约时报畅销书榜上。
It's been on The New York Times Best Seller List ever since.
在这25年里，
During those 25 years,
保罗· 柯艾略出版了30部小说，
Paulo Coelho has published 30 novels
已经以80种不同的语言
that have sold over 165 million copies
出售了超过1.65亿本。
altogether in 80 different languages.
他是在世作家中唯一一个
He is the only living author
被翻译作品比莎士比亚还多的。
more translated than Shakespeare.
保罗和克里斯已经结婚30多年了，
Paulo and Chris have been married for over 30 years
他们还将一起生活下去。
and continue walking together.